Mysteries in History, with your host, Peter Graves.
历史疑案 欢迎主持人
..@ quasi-government agency, the Men in Black...
但是一个半官方的组织 黑衣人
. supposedly carries out operations here on Earth...
一直在地球上秘密的活动着
..in order to keep us safe from aliens throughout the galaxies.
他们 不遗余力地保护着 我们不受外星人的侵略
Here is one of their stories that "never happened"...
接下来的这个故事 也许从未发生过
...from one of their files that doesn't exist.
因为记载它的档案 根本就不存在
1978, The leaders of Zartha flee their planet...
1978年 萨塔星球的首领们
...in order to escape the clutches of the evil Kylothian, Serleena.
纷纷出走
Arriving on Earth, the Zarthans bring with them their greatest treasure:
他们把最珍贵的宝物带到了地球
The Light of Zartha, a cosmic force so powerful...
萨塔之光 这一威力强大的
...that in the wrong hands it could lead to the annihilation of Zartha.
宇宙力量
The Zarthans' princess, Lauranna, beseeched the Men in Black...
萨塔公主葛娜县求黑衣人
...to hide the Light from Serleena.
收藏萨塔之光
But they had no choice.
但他们恕难从命
Intervention would have meant the destruction of the Earth.
插手此事将导致地球毁灭
However, in an act of galactic bravery, the Men in Black subdued Serleena...
然而 赁着无比的勇气 黑衣人从蛇莲娜手中
..allowing the Zarthans to escape...
救出了萨塔旺人
...80 they might hide the Light on another planet.
并将萨塔之光藏在了别的星球
Serleena, released from her captors, vowed that the Light would be hers...
蛇莲娜发拉要得到萨塔之光 并毁灭任何胆敢
..and that she would destroy any planet that stood in her way.
阻止她的星球
And so, never knowing what happened...
就这样 尽管无人知晓
..the people of Earth were saved by a secret society of protectors...
地球人再一次被这些神秘的 保护者拯救 他们就是
...Known as the Men in Black.
黑衣人
Harvey, get over here!
险雷 哈雷 快过来
Harvey. Heel, heel!
哈雷 乖 乖
You're barking at the moon, moron.
别对着月亮叫 傻瓜
Harvey. Harvey!
哈雷 哈雷
Hey, pretty lady.
嘿 大美人
You taste good.
味道不错
Hey, what the--?
嘿 怎么
Yeah, you too.
咽 你也是
Nothing fancy, no heroics. By the book.
别扮酷 也别带能 按规矩来
Got it. Hey!
好 嘿
Hey, Jeff. What's happening, buddy?
嘿 杰弗 我末爱的伙计
-We were wondering why you're here. -The man's talking to you.
怎么了 你没事跑这儿来干吗 和你说话呢
You know our arrangements. Stay in the E, F and R subway lines...
了珀 你还记得我们协议吗 杰弗 你哪儿都不能去 只能呆在地铁E F
..and you get all the garbage you want.
和R号线里面
What the hell are you doing here, worm boy?
随便你想吃多少垃圾都可以 你他妈的到底在干嘛 死虫子
Tee.
了旺 T
Excuse my partner. He's new and he's...
了吐 请你原谅 我这搭挡是新来的 脑子有点
You getting big, Jeff. Boy, what you been eating?
你变胖了 杰弗 吃了什么
You like jokes, huh?
哦 你想玩玩是吗
All right.
啊
Sweet dreams, big boy.
做个好梦 小胖子
Sweet dreams...
做个好梦 啊
.. big boy.
小胖子
Transit authority. Move to the forward car.
地铁管理处 女士们先生们
We got a bug in the electrical system.
请到前面的车而去 我们的电路 系统里有个大虫子
People! We got a bug in the electrical system!
起来 我们的电路系统里 有个 大虫子
Now y'all running?
哦 现在知道跑了
No, no, no! Sit down!
别走 别走 坐下 坐下
It's only a 600-foot worm.
只是个大虫子而已
-Everybody out. -Put the hammer down on this thing.
你们都给我让开 不然别怪我不客气 进去 把列车马力开到最大
I'm Captain Larry Bridgewater. I decide what happens.
我是列车长拉里。布里奇沃特 这里我说了算
You decide? Okay, come here. Come here.
哦 你说了算 哦 好的 过来 过来
Larry? That's my man, Jeff.
拉里 好 这是我朋友 杰弗
-Larry just made a decision. -Larry need to take his ass in there.
拉里刚做了个决定 对 拉里应该回去开车 对
Don't make me do this, Jeff!
别逼我开枪 杰弗
Eighty-first Street.
81大街到了
Just a second.
请等一下
May I have your attention, please?
好了 请大家注意了
We thank you for participating in our drill.
我们衷心的感谢大家参与 这次演习活动
Had this been an emergency, you'd have been eaten.
我想 如果这不是演习的话 你们已经被吃掉了
Because you don't listen. You're ignorant.
因为你们不听话 愚昧无知
How a man gonna bash through--? That's the problem with New Yorkers.
你们怎么不想想我为什么会从车厅 外面飞进来 这就是你们纽约人的通病
"We've seen it all. A 600-foot worm! Save us, Mr. Black Man!"
我们什么没见过 是大虫子 救救我们 黑衣人先生
l ask you nice, "Move to the next car." You just sit there like--
我礼瑶对你们说 请到前一节车厢去 你们却坐着不动 就像
Thank you for participating.
感谢各位参与我们的演习
Hopefully, you enjoyed our smaller, energy-efficient subway cars.
我衷心的希望你们能够喜欢 这个小型节能的地铁列车
Watch your step. You will have a nice evening.
小心脚下 祝今晚过得愉快
I need a cleanup crew at 81st and Central Park West.
马上派清理小组到地铁81大街站 和中央公园西街进行清理
Revoke Jeff's movement privileges.
立刻撤消外星人杰弗的活动许可
Have him escorted to the Chamber Street station.
越快越好 派人把它送回查伯大街 它应该采的位置
And please check the expiration date on the unipod worm tranquilizers.
拜托你们好好查一下虫子麻栈剂 是不是已经过了有效期了
Sorry, fellas. Station closed.
对不起 伙计们 地铁已经关了
-Emergency drill. For your safety. -Do you believe these putzes?
紧急演习 安全第一 你觉得演习有用吗
You're welcome.
不客气
I know, by the book.
我知道 按规矩来
Tee, when was the last time we just looked at the stars?
T 我们最后一次一起看星星 是什么时候
This is a test. 1 can do this.
你是在考我 这我知道
Ever feel like you're alone in the universe?
你有没有觉得我们在宇宙中很孤独
Yes.
是啊
No.
不
-Hey, let me buy you a piece of pie. -Really?
嘿 我请你吃个派 真的
Thanks.
谢谢
Hey, you're not alone in the universe.
嘿 在宇宙中你并不孤独
-Remove the arm. -Okay.
把手拿开 好吧
Please, shut up, Charlie.
给我闭嘴，查理
I'm tired of you constantly talking behind my back.
对于你老是在我背后说话的行为 我已经受够了
You meet a girl. She's into it. The best line you come up with is:
每次你遇见漂亮的女孩 就说不出什么好话
"Wanna come back to my place for some tonsil hockey and egg salad?"
老是那句 想不想去 我家里吃些鸡蛋色拉 你就不会说一些别的
-Who are you and how'd you get in here? -You like egg salad?
哇 你是谁 怎么进来的 来吃鸡蛋色拉的
Serleena!
驼莲娜
Why didn't you say it was you?
我不说我还真 认不出你呢
-Where's the Light? -Here's the deal.
我收到消息 萨塔之光
You're looking for this Light. We found it.
做个交易吧 你在找萨塔之光 告诉你我们已经找到了那个东西
You want it, it'll cost you 50 mill. Here's how it'll work. First--
如果你想要的话 那么就拿五千万出来 美人 按照我说的做 首先 你
Where is the Light?
那东西 在哪儿
We couldn't find it, but we found a guy who might know where it is.
我们没找到萨塔之光 不过我们找到了一个人 他知道在哪里
He runs a pizza parlor on Spring Street.
他在春天大街上开了一家比萨店
Let's go. And wipe your nose, idiot.
带我去“”控一下鼻子 白痴
-Good pie. -Yeah.
哦 真好吃
Crowded.
对 人真多
Well, they got good pie.
这里的派很出名
What is wrong with you?
嘿 你为什么哭啊
-You're gonna neuralyze me. -No, I'm not.
你要消除我记忆 不 不会
You took me here so I wouldn't make a scene.
会 你会的 你把我带到这里来 是为了不让我难堪
You making a scene.
你别这样
Let me ask you a question. Why did you join MiB?
好 我问你个问题 你为什么要做黑衣人
Six years in the Marines. l like the action. Protect the planet.
我当了6年兵 我喜欢战斗的感觉 我想捍卫地球
You like being a hero? You joined the wrong organization.
你想当英雄 看样子你来错地方了
-You ever heard of James Edwards? -No.
你听过和詹姆斯。爱德华吗 没有
Well, he saved the lives of 85 people on the subway tonight.
好 我告诉你 和詹姆斯。爱德华 今晚救了85个人
No one knows he exists.
但是没人知道他存在
And if no one knows he exists, how can anyone ever love him?
既然没人知道他存在 那么又怎么会热爱他
Hey, how long we been partners?
嘿 我们做搭档多久了 二月开始
-Feb 1. -Five months, three days.
5个月 零3天
-Started at noon. -Nine hours.
中午开始 9小时
Get married. Have a bunch of kids.
结婚吧 生一群孩子
Okay.
好的
Excuse me. My buddy's kind of shy, but he thinks you are hot.
对不起 听 我兄弟很怕羞 但他觉得你很 性感
Here it is.
快看啊
I don't know what to say.
我真不知该说什么
Years from now, you know what people'll say?
你知道多年以后 大家看了这个会怎么说
-"Employee" is misspelled? -They charge by the letter.
员工的员写错了 那是按笔画收钱的 人们会说
They'll say, "Imagine that. Big shot like her used to work here."
看啊 她那样的大人物 也在这儿打过工
-Ben-- -You deserve it.
本 我 这你应得的
Bring up a case of Mountain Dew from the basement.
到仓库搬一箱激浪过来 好吗
Hey, Bruno.
嘿 布鲁诺
Two slices of pepperoni and information about the Light of Zartha.
我要两块香肠比萨 两份饮料 还有任何关于萨塔之光的消息
-Whoever you are, don't hurt me. -Where's the Light, Ben?
我不认识你 请不要伤害我 那东西在哪儿 本
I don't know what you're talking about. Let me down, ma'am.
我不知道你在说什么 请你放我下来 女士
l want to report a robbery--
有人在这打动
There.
那边
Noise.
有声音
Kitchen!
厨房
You idiots see anything?
看到什么没有
Wind blew the door open.
风把门吹开了
Nothing out of the ordinary.
一切都很正常
For 25 years, I've traveled the universe looking for it.
25年来 我为了萨塔之光找遍了宇宙
But it never left Earth, did it? You kept it here.
但其实它从来没有离开过地球 你藏起来了
What are you talking about?
你到底在说什么
I'm running out of time. Where's the Light?
我没有时间跟你玩 告诉我萨塔之光在哪儿
-l don't know what you mean. -Listen, Zarthan.
我发拆 我不懂你什么意思
You hid the Light on Earth. I'll find it.
听着 萨塔人 我知道你把它藏在这里
Once we have the Light, Zartha will be ours.
但我会找到的 一旦我找到了 萨塔就是我们的了
You're too late. Tomorrow at midnight...
你来晚了 明天午夜
..the Light will leave the third planet and be back home.
萨塔之光将离开第三星球 回家
Sorry you made the trip for nothing.
非常抱歉让你白跑了一趟
Now we don't know if it's on Earth or not.
天啊 可我们还是不知道它在哪
He said third planet. It's here, you idiot.
第三星球 就是地球 白痴
-Third Rock from the Sun. -l never got that till now.
太阳系第三星球 我想我现在明白了
It's on Earth, and I know who's gonna tell me where it is.
它在地球上 而且有人会告诉我它的下落
-Don't you ever go home? -Nope.
你从不回家吗 没错
Il see you neuralyzed another partner.
你又开除了一个搭档
Bee, Dee, when you use a fission carbonizer...
D 记得下次用核融碳化枪
.. attach a de-atomizer so it doesn't sound like a cannon.
再加上原子消音器 这样就不会那么吵了
Hey, get some booties on them things. You're crapping up the floor.
是先生 嘿 能不能穿上鞋子 你刮花地板了 我没钱 J
Check his visa.
你过来 去查查这家伙的护照
The Cephalopods have been making counterfeits at Kinko's on Canal.
据调查有一个乌由T人团伙 在伪造星际护照
And why do I have a dead Tricrainasloph going through passport control?
谁能告诉我这儿 怎么会有一个异形尸体
That'd be my fault. I'm very sorry. Please don't neuralyze me, sir.
这是我的错“”对不起 先生 别消除我的记忆 先生
-What the hell's that supposed to mean? -Nothing, sir.
你这么说是什么意思 没什么 先生
Good work in the subway.
在地铁里干得不错
-l remember Jeff when he was yea high. -What you got for me?
我记得杰弗以前就这么点大 有什么新任务
Look. See those guys in black suits?
我想你一定看见底下 那些穿黑西装的了
-They work here. We got it covered. -Zed, what you got?
我们有新伙伴了 说吧 有什么任务
Dedication's one thing, but this job will eat you up and spit you out.
专心工作是好事 但这样的拼命 你会把自己累跨的
You want to look like me when you hit 50...
你不想到了50才还像我一样吧
ish?
50多
I'll be in the gym if you need me.
我会去健身房的
All right, there was a killing earlier. 177 Spring.
好吧 现在有桩凶杀案 春天街177号
Alien-on-alien.
外星人被杀
Take Tee with you and make a report.
带上T一起去 写份报告
You have got to stop neuralyzing MiB personnel.
你不可以总是这样 自作主张把他们开除
He was crying in the middle of the diner.
你吃晚饭的时候哭器啼啼的
I hate that.
我讨厌那样
And plus, you can't count Elle.
还有 你不能把L也算进去
She wanted to go back to the morgue. I helped her.
是她自己想回停尸间工作 我那是帮她
-You need a partner. -I'm cool.
你要个搭档 我不用
I'll be his partner.
让我来吧
Jay, wait up. l appreciate the shot, man.
J 等等 谢谢你的提拔
-Thought I'd never get out. -Lose the suit.
我早就想离开收发室了 把西装脱了
Sure thing. Just going for the look.
好的”搭档 没问题
But if l say so myself, I find it slimming.
我穿西装只是为了好看 难道你不觉得 这样我可以显得更瘦一些
Not that I've had problems with the ladies.
我可不是因为钓不到妞 才穿得这么帅
When you get down to--
哇噢”好酷
Nice sled, very swank.
太漂亮了 椅子软吗
Heated seats? Sometimes I get hives.
我可有阁郊
Frank!
法兰克
Bring your head in this window before I roll it up in there.
拜托你别唱了 把头伸进来 我要关窗了
Got it.
明白
Frank!
法兰克
My money? It's missionary.
就我而言 我最喜欢背式
I was in the Bowery, and I meet this Great Dane.
那次我在纽约认识一条母狗
A little thick in the body, but pretty.
虽然有点胖 但是很漂亮
That's just not appealing to me, man. Seriously.
我对你的艳遇没兴趣
Il say we do the good cop, bad cop thing.
好吧 我们来演好警察 坏警察
You interrogate the witness and I growl.
你去问证人 我来吓距她
How about we do the good cop, dumb dog thing, and you just shut up?
不 不如我们演好警察和笨狗 你快给我闭嘴
You got it, partner. Total silence.
没问题 搭档 保持安静
Absolute quiet. Not a word out of me.
一声不蚁 一个字也不说
What do we got?
什么情况
-What do we got? -There's residue on the wall.
这里到处都是磷的残留物
-We sent samples to Em for analysis. -Hey, 0% body fat.
我们已经取样送去化验了 嘿 」 他竟然没有脂肪
-Funny. -Witness?
好笑 证人昵
Girl. Saw everything.
哦 那个女孩
She's taking it well.
她挺镇静的 听着
Il won't answer any more questions. l want to know what happened here.
你们别老问我问题 我想请你回答我的问题 这到底是怎么回事
-I'll handle this one. -You got it.
交给我来处理 没问题
Alone. A talking dog might be a bit much for her now.
我自己去 要是见到狗说话她会发疯的
What do you want me to do?
那我干吗
Sniff around.
到处闻闻
What?
干吗
Funny.
好笑
Take a deep breath. Everything is all right.
深呼吸 小姐 一切都会好的
What part is she supposed to feel all right about?
等事情过去了 她自然会好的
I'm Agent Jay.
我是J探员
Tell me what you saw.
能不能告诉我你看到了什么
-A two-headed guy and a woman. -Caucasian?
双头人和穿皮衣的女人 白人
Gray, with tentacles that she used to rip--
灰的 当她伸手的 时候有触角可以撕开
His skin off.
撕开他的皮肤
It's not skin. It's protoplasma polymer similar to the gum in baseball cards.
其实那不是皮肤 怎么说呢 那是原生质保护膜 就像口香糖
-What was the last thing you ate? -Calzone.
说说出事前你吃的什么
-What time? -Lunch.
比萨 什么时候
-Spinach? -Mushroom.
中午 菠菜味 蘑菇
You need pie.
咽 我请你吃派
You okay?
你还好吗
An hour ago, a man I've known my whole life vanished...
一个我认识这么久的人被杀了 这让我很难过
.. because of a woman with weird fingers...
更何况凶手 是个手指会伸出
..and a two-headed guy with a cannoli's IQ.
触角的女人 还有一个长着两个头的白痴
So yeah, everything's okay.
哦 是的 简直太好了
When we're kids, before we're taught how to think...
小时候 在去学校受教育之前
..our hearts tell us there is something else out there.
我就知道一定有外星人存在
I know what I saw. Tell me what I'm supposed to believe.
我知道我看到了什么 你说我应该相信吗
I'm a member of a secret organization that monitors alien activity on Earth.
好吧 告诉你 我属于一个秘密组织 专门管理地球上的外星人
Ben was an alien. So were his killers.
本是外星人 凶手也是
I don't know why they did it, but I promise I'm gonna find out.
我不知道他们为什么这么做 但我会查出来的
Okay.
好的
-Okay? -Okay.
好吗 好的
Okay.
好
-I'm sorry, I'm gonna have to-- -Kill me.
阮 抱 呢 我必须要
No!
杀了我 不 不
Just a little flash and everything goes back the way it was.
不 只是 内一下 一切 都恢复原样了
After you flash me...
你照了我 之后
. if lsee you again, will l know it's you?
我再看见你 能认出你吗
I'll see you.
我会来看你
But you won't see me.
但你认不出我
Must be hard.
这样很往昔
Must be very lonely.
你一定很孤单
Excuse me.
对不起
-I gotta go. -What about the flashy thing?
我要走了 那你不照我了吗
I'll flash you some other time.
了珀 晚点再照你吧
What?
干嘛
-Did you tell the girl you love her? -She's a witness to a crime. That's it.
你爱上她了 嘿 她只是凶杀案的证人 就这样
You're attracted. She's not my species, and I'm attracted.
是的 是的 你迷上她了 我和她不同种都迷上她了
I should take advice on love from a dude that chases his own ass?
哦 天啊 一只笨狗 竟然在教我如何追女生
Easy, pal. That's canine profiling, and I resent it.
别这样 你竟然歧视狗 小心我告你
Hey, Jay, wait up.
嘿 J 等等
Coming through. MiB brass. Look sharp.
借过 黑衣人来了 大家好
I'm Agent Eff, Jay's new partner. Who are you eyeballing?
我是狗探员 J的新搭档 你看什么看 哦
Frank, just cool out, dog.
法兰克 安静点
-Got kids? -No.
有孩子吗 没
Want them?
想要吗
Get him off me!
快把它拉开
-Talk to me. -It's Kylothian, class C.
怎么回事 卡罗瑟星C级太空船
Serleena.
驼莲娜
-Serleena. Old girlfriend? -She wishes.
驼莲娜 你前女友 她希望是
The perps were looking for the Light of--
证人说嫌犯在找 萨塔
-Zartha. -Yeah, what is it?
之光 对 那是什么
This makes no sense. It's not on Earth.
这没道理 萨塔之光不在地球上
-We took care of this a long time ago. -Obviously not.
很早以前我们就搞定了 也许并非如此
That is very bad news.
有大麻烦了
The Zarthans came to Earth to hide the Light from Serleena.
25年前 萨塔人想把萨塔之光 藏在地球上
-We don't do that. -Right. I ordered it off the planet.
我们没答应 是的 我命令他们把它带走
Well, Zed....
好吧 2Z
I got a Kylothian class C in my park. Are you sure this Light isn't here?
公园里有一稻卡罗瑟飞船降落 你确定萨塔之光不在这儿
Positive. l gave the order. My best agent carried it out.
当然 当时是我亲自下的命令
-It's as if l gave it to you. -Ask the agent.
还派了顶尖的探员
-Can't. -Dead?
去问下那个探员 不行 死了
Sort of. He works at the post office.
算是 他现在在邮局工作
No.
不
If Serleena gets to Kay before we do, he's dead,
如果K先被蛇莲娜找到 他就死定了
The Earth's very existence may rest on what Kay knows.
现在地球的命运就掌握在他的手中
Too bad you wiped out his memory of it.
可惜你消除了他的记忆
Bring him in.
带他来
Now.
现在
How cool is this? Going to get Kay. The legend, the go-to guy.
好棒 去找K 英雄 传奇人物
The guy who taught you everything.
你的导师 教会你一身本领
-The greatest agent in MiB history! -Frank! Stop talking.
历史上最强的黑衣人 法兰克 别再说了
Stay.
采在这
Listen, partner. I may look like a dog...
嘿 上听着 搭档 我也许看上去像条狗
.. but l only play one here on Earth.
但我只是拿着作掩护 哦
-Whatever. Wipe your mouth. -Hey, babe.
随便 把嘴控一下 嘿 宝贝
People of Truro, may I kindly have your attention?
各位麻省楚罗镇的居民们 大家注意了
To facilitate your shipping needs...
为了运输的方便
..all packages must be properly wrapped.
请大家正确包装邮件 你们看 这就是一个不正确的例子
This one is an example of "go home and do it again."
这个包硝非常漂亮 但它将被退回
Il think you know what I mean, Mrs. Vigushin.
你明白我的意思吧 冯太太
Brown paper and triple-twist twine are the preferred media.
记住牛皮纸和麻强 是标准的 包法
Thank you for your time.
谢谢各位
-Kay. -C. Express mail, two-day air.
K 5 空运信件 两天到达
Kevin.
凯文
Kevin. That's funny. You don't have a "Kevin"...
哇 这太好笑了 你竟然叫 凯文
You don't remember. We worked together.
你不记得我 我 我们一起工作过
I never worked in a funeral home. Something I can do for you, slick?
我没在殡仪馆工作过 有什么可以帮你吗
Straight to the point.
好吧 呢 我就直说吧
You were an agent of an organization that monitors aliens on Earth.
你属于一个专门管理地球上的 外星人的政府秘密组织
We're the Men in Black. We have a situation. We need your help.
黑衣人 我们现在非常需要你
There is a free mental health clinic on the corner of Lilac.
隔壁镇上的一家 免费的精神病院非常适合你
-Next. -Excuse me.
下一位 借过
-Twenty Rugrats stamps. -Elizabeth.
嘿 20张小兵邮票
The Postal Service hasn't kept up with today's youth, but we have...
哦 对不起 邮政总里总是跟不上流行 不过我有些二战纪念邮票
...Berlin airlift stamps. Opera legends?
不知道你是不是喜欢 不 电影明星 不
American Samoa? Amish quilts.
萨摩亚群岛 不 阿什米人
I'm sorry, got a world to save here.
对不起 宝贝 我们要拯救地球
There was no coma. It was a cover.
你当年没有氏迷 只是个赐子
-Who are you?
你是谁 问题是 你是谁
The postmaster of Truro, Massachusetts, and I'm ordering you to leave.
我是楚罗镇邮局局长 现在我命令你马上离开 K
-ls that decaf? -Sorry.
没加糖 对不起
We have a breach. Cordon off this area.
好了 我们有客人来了 费罗
Full perimeter wipe-down, right here, right now.
封锁现场 比利 彻底清除现场
Get a mop and escort all civilian personnel from this site immediately.
K 费罗 请你立即将闲杂人等 赶出邮局 是 先生
Listen to yourself, Kay. Who talks like that?
你自己上听听吧 K 谁这么说话
Why do you think you're so comfortable here?
你在这里过得挺舒服
Just about everybody who works in a post office is an alien.
邮局里几乎所有人都是外星人
No smoking.
不许抽烟
Kay.
K
My wife and I saw Siegfried and Roy fly a tiger around a room.
在赌城 我妻子和我见过 魔术师让老虎飞起来
You're nothing special.
你的把戏不过如此
When you look at the stars, you get a feeling...
当你抬头看夜空 其实你
. like you don't know who you are.
并不知道自己到底是谁
Like you know more about out there than you do down here.
你对宇宙的了解远远多过地球
That's why she left you, Kay. That's why your wife left you.
所以她才离开你 所以你妻子才离开你
Okay, I'll tell you what.
好吧 如果
You want to know who you really are, take a ride with me.
你想知道你到底是谁 我带你去个地方
If not, people are waiting for their TV Guides.
不然 就快回去送信吧
Think he'll bite?
他会来吗
I'm just going for a ride. If things don't add up, it's hasta luego.
如果你页花样 我马上就走 懂我意思吗
Hey, Kay.
嘿 嘿
How's it hanging?
过得好吗
Good to see you, Kay.
很高兴见到你 K
Good to see you too, whoever you are.
我也很高兴 不管你是谁
Well, let's see what you got here, chief.
好吧 我就跟你去看看
Welcome back, Agent Kay.
欢迎回来 K探员
Agent Kay.
K探员
Greetings, Kay.
你好 K
Wow, look who's back.
我听说过他
I don't mean to bother you-- You're Agent Kay!
哦 K回来了 J探员 天啊 你是K探员
-That's what they tell me. -This is an honor. Agent Gee.
大家都这么叫我 太荣幸了 我是6
The most respected agent in MiB history.
天啊 史上最受人尊敬的黑衣人
The most feared human in the universe.
宇宙中最令人敬畏的人
Maybe I could buy you a cup of coffee?
可以请你喝杯咖啡吗 然后听你讲故事
-Black, two sugars, if you're going. -An honor.
两块糖不要奶 谢谢你 马上好
-Yeah, I'll take a-- My man? -Good to see you, Kay.
欢迎回来 Kk探员 拜托 我想带 我朋友
How'd it go?
情况如何
The Drolacks are gone and the treaty is signed.
多啦人走了 条约也签了
Good work.
干得好
What about that position you promised me in Men in Black?
2Z 那我加入星际战警的事 怎么样了
Still working on the alien affirmative action program.
我在蕉你争取 外星人的保障名额
That's not what you promised me.
等一下 你以前答应过我的
-You're breaking up. -Zed? Hello?
线路有问题 我听不清 我再打给你
-I'll call you back. - could be Agent Em. Zed, you--
我可以当W探员 2Z 你听我说
I think Earth might be in a bad way. You're the only one that could save it.
K 地球有危险了 看来只有你可以救她了
-Well, neither rain, sleet, snow.... -Good man.
是啊 邮差总是风雨无阻 好样的
Get him armed and up to speed and over to deneuralyzation.
给他装备武器 带他去恢复记忆
-Frank? -Yeah?
法兰克 在
I'm gonna need them together on this one.
我要他俩一起行动 喔
I need an assistant. It's not field work, but you get dental.
我要一个新助手 提供牙医保险
Dental?
牙医
Allis lost! Allis lost!
噢 天啊 噢 天啊
Don't touch that!
别碰那个
I didn't do anything.
我什么都没干
Hands in your pockets.
手 揪在口袋里
Your favorite weapon.
你的最爱
-That? -Yep.
这个 是
-Let's go put it on. -What?
把衣服穿上 什么
The last suit you'll ever wear.
你最后穿过的这套
Again.
来吧 去
The deneuralyzer.
记忆恢复咒
Magneto-energy will surge through your brain...
逆转磁能量将通过你的大脑
.. Unlocking information that could hold the key to Earth's very survival.
找到你沉睡的记忆 把它唤酝 你的那段记忆 能够拯救整个地球
Okay. What's that thing?
好吧 那是什么
The deneuralyzer.
记忆恢复咒
Welcome to planet Earth. There are some rules and regulations.
欢迎来地球 有些规矩你要知道
Go out only at night.
你只能晚上出门
If you must go out during the daylight, only the East Village.
如果一定要白天出去 只能去东区
Name and planet of origin?
姓名来自哪里
Sylona Gorth. Planet Jorn. Kaluth system.
蛇莲娜。高斯 卓恩星球 卡鲁星系
-Any fruits or vegetables? -Yeah, two heads of cabbage.
携带蔬果了吗 两颗卷心菜
Reason for visit?
来访目的
Education. I want to learn how to be an underwear model.
学习 我想成为一个内衣模特
They told me I've got real potential.
他们说我很有潜力
Help! Heart attack!
救命 心脏病
Wake up, champ!
快醒醒 伙计
-Oh, jeez. -Lockdown. Code 101.
哦 天啊 封锁
Lockdown.
封锁 代号101
This is not good. This is not good.
看起来不妙 看起来不钞
-Breach! We're being flushed. -Flushed?
出事了 我们会被冲出去 冲出去 对
-Ever been to a water park? -I don't know.
去过水上乐园吗 不记得了
Flushed.
哦 冲吧
Yeah, man, back when you was an agent, you loved getting flushed.
你以前当黑衣人的时候 最喜欢被冲了
Yeah, every Saturday night, you'd be like, "Flush me, Jay. Flush me."
每到周六晚上 你就会乱叫 冲我吧 J 冲我
I'd be like, "No."
我说 不
You can't quit on me.
你现在不能丢下我
Il save the world, you tell me why I stare at the stars.
我拯救地球 你告诉我过去的一切
Does that come standard?
这是标准配置吗
It came with a black dude, but he kept getting pulled over.
本来是黑人开 不过总是被警察拦住
I could rule this place with the right set of mammary glands.
一群白痴 漂亮女人就能统治地球
Trapped like rats...
惨了 逃不了了
..in a Chia Pet.
被困住了
Computer, surveillance MiB.
电脑连接总部
MiB's locked down.
总部封锁了
Computer, magnify. Times 10.
电脑放大十倍 再放大
Communicator. Frank.
请接法兰克
-Jay, where are you? -We got flushed.
J 你在哪里 被冲出来了
-MiB's code 101. -Yeah, who did it?
安全代号101 谁干的
Some hot-looking biker chick. Want me to tail her?
一个身材火爆的美女 要跟踪吗
-Stay where you are. I'll be in touch. -Stay where I am. Easy for you to say.
拜托原地待命 是 原地待命 你说得轻巧
-Find Kay? -Neuralyzed.
找到K了吗 他失忆了
-Not active. Civilian. -What?
变成 普通人 什么
-He was-- -Here.
他过来 这里
-To get-- -Deneuralyzed.
来恢复记忆 恢复记忆
-Memory's shot. But we'll find him. -Don't put anything in our ears.
别发火 我们会找到他 别再插我们耳秒了
What?
干嘛
What do you make of that? Found it in my pocket. Weird, huh?
我在衣袋里找到的 奇怪吧
-Yeah, a smile. -ls that the only deneuralyzer?
是的你在笑 只有那一台记忆恢复器吗
Officially. The plans leaked out on the Internet.
只做一台 但是几年前蓝图泄漏了
Computer, Internet.
电脑上网
Deneuralyzer.
记忆恢复咒
Perfect. It's an old friend.
太好了 是个老朋友
Jay, ain't seen you in a while.
嘿 J好久不见
Did you peep that drop-top thing out front?
有没有看到对画 那是我的敞禾车
My business is banging, dog.
我的生意红火极了
You gotta check out the website. It's Jeebsie dot--
你应该去我的网站看看 Jeebsie. com
Okay, whoa. He's retired, right?
噢 他不是退休了吗
We need the deneuralyzer.
我们要用记忆恢复器
-You're kidding. -The meter's running, Jeebs.
别开玩笑 别浪费时间
Do you remember me?
你 还认得我吗
Can't say I do. I'm good with faces.
记不得了 脸很熟 也许
I think I'd remember that.
会想起来
The great Kay's a neutral.
哈哈 伟大的K失忆了
You're between me and my memories. Do you have this deneuralyzer or not?
咽 你在浪费我宝贵的时间 到底有没有记忆恢复器
No.
没
Fresh out.
卖光了
Can't help you.
帮不了你
Don't got it.
没货了
Even if I did, if it doesn't work, he dies, you blow my head off.
就算有 如果没效果的话 你会亡掉我脑袋
If it does, I've brought back Kay, who, for fun, blows my head off.
如果有效 K 恢复了记忆 他还会筷掉我脑袋
So, what's my incentive?
那 我有什么好处
Okay, homey, I keep it downstairs next to the snow blowers.
好吧 伙计 我藏在楼下 在除雪机边上
Alien prisoners released, armed and ready for your orders.
外星囚犯被释放 听候您的差遣
Prisoners of MiB, the scum of the universe.
宇宙中的坏蛋们 你们都听好了
Now it's the scum's turn.
现在是我们做主
I'm in a jam, so I'll make this simple.
我赶时间 所以长话短说
I need the Light of Zartha, and Kay knows where it is.
我要萨塔之光 K知道在哪儿
Whoever brings Kay to me gets Earth.
所以 找到K就可以统治地球
Find a deneuralyzer. They want his memory back.
去找记忆恢复咒 他一定在恢复记忆
Check.
遵命
Now.
出发
Jarra, good to see you.
贾拉幸会了
Okay, that should do it.
K 应该可以了
If l could have your attention while we go over the safety procedures.
现在我来给你仔细说明一下 安全守则
Keep your hands inside the vehicle.
请勿将手或脚伸出机器外
If, during the ride, you become disoriented...
如果你觉得头型脑胀 那么我
.. there's nothing we can do about it.
我也毫无办法
Have you removed all your jewelry?
你把首饰都拿掉了吗
-Are you allergic to shellfish? -Jeebs!
那么你对贝类食物过敏吗
Right, then! Smoke 'em if you got 'em.
杰克 开始 抽根烟吧
Have you used this?
你用过这玩意吗
l used it to make some hot-air popcorn. That's about it.
阮 我以前用排气管烤过爆米花
Okay! Let's make it happen, cap'n!
好吧 让我们开始吧
Perfect.
太好了
-You're back. -No.
想起来了 没
-How'd you know his head grows back? -It grows back?
怎么知道他的头会再生 会再生
Real nice. Okay, that's the last time Il help out a friend.
太好了 我以后再也不会帮你了
-Kay, you remember anything? -Goodbye.
K 你都想起来了 再见
-Kay! -Kay, wait!
K K 等等
I never got the updated software. Still working off the 6.0.
我的机器一直没有更新系统 还得用6. 0版
Your brain needs to reboot.
你的大脑 需要重启
Give it a minute.
请等一下 K
Kay!
K 我真的很抱才
Bottom of my heart, I'm really sorry. l hope it won't affect our friendship.
J 太对不起了
All those years of loyalty and trust, respect for one another.
这么多年来 我们一直相互信任 相互尊敬
Right over there!
他在那
-Where's Kay? -He's not here! He went--
K 在哪
Kay's retired. I'm his trigger-happy replacement.
他已经退休了 我是他的接班人 我能为你们做什么
Right in the pie hole. Now nothing's gonna taste right.
正好打在嘴里 现在吃什么都不香了
-Lower your weapon. -No.
放下武器 不
Jay, how are you, boo-boo?
J 你怎么样 宝贝
-These guys really need Kay. -He's a neutral.
看 这些家伙在找K
-Tell me something we don't know. -Yeah, tell me something--
他失忆了 说点我们不知道的 是啊 说点我们
lam so sorry.
真对不起
-God bless you. -Thank you.
保重 谢谢
If 1 don't bring Kay back to MiB, Serleena's gonna kick my ass.
听着 如果找不到K的话 蛇莲娜会踢烂我的屁股
-Now, where is he? -Where is who?
他在哪儿 你说谁
You don't look too good.
你看起来不妙啊
Yeah, and you look like crap.
你看起来像堆屎
l take that back. He look like crap.
我说错了 是他看起来像堆屎
-Bend him! -Bend him.
干掉他 干掉他们
Wait, don't bend him.
嘿 等等 别干掉他们
Damn decent of you.
多谢 脚下留情
Don't mention it.
不客气
-I'm gonna be sick. -You don't wanna do that.
我快要吐了 千万别吐
-Fellas, I think he's telling the truth. -Then he's no good to us.
我觉得他说得有道理 他对我们没用
-Didn't l teach you anything, kid? -Pineal eye!
我没教过你吗 小子 打眼睛
Go for the mosh tendrils!
拉他的胡须
-You were in a tight spot. -l handled it.
你差点没命 小子 我没事 放心
-You need a partner. -l had one. Job got too tough.
你需要搭档 有过 后来他不干了
I'm back. You got some dust on your coat.
我回来了 你的衣服脏了
So you got your memory back.
那么 你都想起来了 对
-What the hell is going on? -Don't know.
这怎么回事 不知道
-The Light of Zartha? -Never heard of it.
萨塔之光是什么 没听说过
Cool.
好吧
You don't remember the Light of Zartha?
你说你不记得萨塔之光
Must've neuralyzed myself to keep it from myself.
我一定是为了保密 消除了这部分记忆
-Good plan. What you doing? -I do the driving.
好方法 等等 你要干嘛
-Wait, no. Whoa. -l remember that.
我开车啊 等等 不不不 这我会
What you remember is you used to drive that old, busted jawn.
你只会开那种土得 掉漆的老坦克
I drive the new hotness.
看 我的 可是最新款
Old and busted, new hotness.
你开破车 我开好车
Old busted hotness.
我的车完了
-Serleena, please. -Been a long time, Zed.
驼莲娜 请你 好久不见 Z
I'm just touched you remembered me. Makes me fuzzy all over.
你竟然还记得我 我真的好感动
Never forget a pretty whatever you are.
我不会忘记 你的美丽
Zed?
Z 2Z
Zed? Look at you.
看看你
Twenty-five years, and you're still such a looker.
25年不见了 你还是那么的帅
Cut out the meat and dairy.
我坚持吃素
And you, still a pile of squirmy crap in a different wrapper.
不过看看你 换了外型 不过还是一样恶心
So feisty. Look, we both need the same thing.
哦 去你的 听着 2Z 我们都在找同一样东西
Bring him in.
叫他来
Don't think so.
想都别想
What about the Light's secret? If it's not off Earth by midnight...
你还记得萨塔之光吗 如果午夜前不离开地球
.. it self-destructs, annihilating your little planet.
它就会自爆 毁灭这个星球
Il lose, you lose. I win, everything keeps spinning.
我给 你也输 我赢 一切都会照旧
You don't want the Light on Earth any more than I do.
你也不想把它留在地球上吧
All right, Serleena.
好吧 蛇莲娜
You win.
你赢了
Zed? Is that you? ! could be Agent Em.
Z 是你吗 我可以当探员W
Zed. Hello?
Z
So feisty.
真是个废物
Fastest way back to MiB, you take this right on 39th.
去总部最快的路是39街
Right here. Right.
右转
Next right on 37th.
右 下一个再转
Right here. Right!
这里 转弯 转
We're not going back.
我们不去总部
Headquarters has been breached, man. We need to peel caps and split wigs.
总部已经被占领了 难道我们不应该 先冲进去 大开杀戒 救出大家吗
Not ready.
没到时候
Look, you've been out for five years. That's a long time.
瞧 你离开5年 有很长时间了
l understand you're scared. I'm a little scared too.
我知道你有点害怕 不过这没关系
-I'm not scared. -Me neither.
我也有点害怕 我不怕 我也不
I just thought we was bonding.
我 我只是随便说说
You're acting like a rookie. Splitting wigs and stepping on caps.
五年了 你还像个菜鸟 打打杀杀 只知道变干
-No wonder Zed brought me back. -He did it because you messed up.
难怪Z要我回来 拜托 Z叫你回来 是因为你搞古了
Your attitude makes for a stressful environment.
你这种态度对工作 没有任何帮助
Tell it to the hand. Stressful is what we got back at MiB.
别对我说教 总部现在需要帮助 他们需要我们
Exactly. Serleena broke into MiB in order to lure me back.
蛇莲娜想引我去总部 说出萨塔之光的下落
Into a trap.
是陷阱
Which is why we can't bust in there.
所以我们不应该冲进去 不回总部也该有个去处吧
We need a plan. Where we going? Scene of the crime?
我们去哪 犯罪现场
-You're the boss. -Scene of the crime. That's a left.
你说了算 好 犯罪现场 往 往左转
I'll contact the witness. We'll talk to her.
我们到了 找证人谈谈
Things have changed. We used to neuralyze witnesses.
放在以前 我们会消除他们记忆
See, originally, I'd--
本来我 咽 我喝 本来想是要
No, I was going to-- l interrogated her.
咽 问过话以后 消除她的记忆
-Then neuralyzed her? -What?
什么意思
MiB code 773I-1 clearly states that all civilian personnel--
工作守则第773条 第一小条规定 所有的平民百姓
-Drop that weapon! -No!
噢 放下武器 不不不
Jay, I'm-- I'm sorry.
J 对不起
No, no, I'm fine. It's my fault.
没事 我没事 是我不好
Kay, my partner. Laura, the witness.
了听 K 我搭档 葛拉 凶案证人
Pleasure.
幸会
Thanks for sending those agents over to keep an eye on me last night.
J 真是谢谢你派探员整个晚上 在这保护我 你真好
MiB procedural code 594-B...
工作守则594条B款规定
.. States that MiB personnel shall never be used--
黑衣人 在任何情况下 都不可以
Ben, the Zarthan, was vaporized here. l assume the perp was over here.
本 萨塔星人 在这里被害 我猜 凶手应该在 那个位置
Ben.
本
-Was he 5'7", thinning hair? -You knew him?
5尺7寸高 有点秃头 你认识他
Nope. Never seen him before in my life.
不 这几有照片
That is a hell of a fish.
这鱼可真大
Wait a minute.
等等
You left yourself clues?
你留下了线索
In case I was deneuralyzed because my replacement couldn't handle it.
对 以免我消除记忆后 我的接班人找不到头绪
If the joker that had got deneuralyzed hadn't created the situation--
好了 听着”是你把事情搞策 才会变成现在这样
Boys.
是你的错 别吵了
All right. You pointing at something.
好吧 你指着什么
Excuse me.
对不起
The astronaut.
宇航员
Jay?
J
Okay, all right. He's pointing....
看 他在指
He's like...
他是在
Who would stack boxes like this?
谁会这样堆比萨盒子
A box stacker who's not stacking boxes. He's leaving clues.
这绝对不是随便乱放的
It's an arrow.
有箭头
-Jay? -You're slowing me down, slick.
J 你影响我工作了
Whatever we're looking for is in these cabinets, right here.
我们要找的东西在这些柜子里
Anchovy filets in virgin olive oil.
橄榄油泡的鳗鱼罐头
I hope I'm not slowing you down.
我希望这没有影响你
Good work, partner. Yeah.
干得好 搭档 对
-We gotta figure out where it goes. -l know where.
查出这是哪的钥匙 我知道 哦K
-No. Not yet. -MiB code 773 clearly says--
等一下 工作守则773条明确规定
I know the code, but she might be important to me.
我知道规矩 但是她对我很重要
To us. Well, for help. To help us later.
对我们 她可以 可以帮助我们
Well, she can't stay here. They'll be back.
她不能留在这儿
-You can stay with friends of mine. -People like you?
你可以呆在我朋友那 和你一样
Kind of.
差不多
-Low bridge! -What's going on, man?
J 小心头 过得怎样啊 老兄
Hey, what's happening, fellas? MiB is code 101.
总部被占领 代号101
-Bad. -Very bad.
糟糕 太糟粒
-l need your help. This is Laura. -Laura!
我需要你们的帮忙 这是萝拉
Easy, easy!
葛拉 嘿安静
They're worms.
是虫子
Once you go worm, that's what you'll yearn.
和虫子做朋友 什么事都不用愁
-That's what they say. They just: -I've dated worse.
是啊 人们都这么说 他们只是 我能应付
They're suspended for stealing from duty-free.
他们因为在免税店偷东西 被停职了
-We were framed. -Zed's wormophobic.
我们是被冤枉的 Z 他怕虫子
-Kay! -You're back!
K
-They said you were dead. -We're double-parked.
我还以为你死了 气色不错啊 我们没时间了
Laura's very important to me.
对 萝拉对我很重要
To us. To the stuff-- Me and you, the stuff we're doing.
我们 对我们的任务很重要
-Keep an eye on her. -I'll keep both on her.
帮我好好照看她 好吗
No problem!
我会照料她的 没问题
-Why don't you sit here? -Like you got a shot.
坐这 嘿嘿嘿 你没希望的啦 你给我闭嘴
My communicator, in case you need it.
我的通讯器 你拿着吧
-Nice move. -Okay.
好吧味 哦
-Just watch out for Neeble. -Which one's Neeble?
小心点尼伯 哪只是尼伯
-Which one of y'all is Neeble? -Yo, mama!
哪只是尼伯 嘿 是我
Him, right there. It's fine. Everything's straight. It's safe.
他号 没有问题了 这很安全
Don't fall asleep.
呢 不要睡着
Twister!
玩游戏
Run over your plan one more time. I'm struggling with it.
K再说一次你的计划吧 把我都有点搞糊涂了
You neuralyzed memory of the Light but left yourself clues.
你消除了萨塔之光的记忆 但是留下了线索方便查找
Right.
对
Photo pointing to a key in a pizzeria which opens a locker at Grand Central.
一张照片指向一把挂着钥匙 据说可以打开中央车站的一个柜子
-In the locker, we'll find another clue. -That's the plan.
对 这个柜子应该是另一个线索 就是这样
-l like to keep my enemies confused. -We're all confused.
哈 我想要迷惑敌人 我们都被迷惑了 K
-Are you gonna slow me down? -Your brain's working on old software.
别妨碍我办事 谁的大脑用的是过时软件啊
Why don't you go grab us some coffee?
可不可以去买两杯咖啡
Sure. How do you take it? Black? Couple cubes of kiss my ass?
哦 当然 要糖吗 不如 我帮你现磨吧
I don't know what's in there, so step back.
我不知道里面是什么 请你 让开
Kay, for real, man. Open the damn locker.
嘿K 拜托 快打开吧
Kay! He's back! The light giver!
K 他回来了 光的使者 光的使者
All hail Kay! All hail Kay!
K 万上 K 万宙
Oh, Kay, can you see By the dawn's early light
喔 K 你看见没 你赐给我们光明
You are the man who would be king of the train locker.
想不到你还是储物柜救世主
Praise Kay!
你赐予了光明 K 万鹤 K 万内
Oh, good and gentle townsfolk of Locker C-18...
哦 C18储物柜的亲爱的 子民们
-...did l leave anything here? -Yes. The timekeeper.
我留下什么东西吗 是的 时光器
Left to illuminate our streets and hearts.
它照亮了街道和我们的心
-I've been looking everywhere for this. -Merciful one! The clock tower!
我就要找他 噢 枇悲的主 灯塔不见了
I got y'all, it's cool. Check this out.
不 我来 这样 这样 我有办法
Titanium case. Waterproof to over 300 meters.
钛合金外过的300米防水 而且是
-That's banging. -Who are you, stranger?
最新款的 陌生人 你是谁
Jay.
J
All hail Jay!
虽 J 万上风 J 万风
Oh, Jay, can you see
噢 J你看见没 你赐给我们光明
-Oh, merciful Jay, the keeper of-- -Come on.
仁枇的 J 光明使者
-Wait! The commandments! -The tablet!
等等 还有戒规
The tablet! The tablet!
戒规 戒规
We have lived by its word, and peace has reigned throughout our world.
我们一直遵守戒规 和平相处
Pass it on to others! So that they too may be enlightened!
互相教导 让大众得救 (发烧友影带商店)
Be kind! Rewind!
善良 忠诚
Reconcile your past...
反省过去
..in order to move into your future!
才能有美好的未来
Two for one every Wednesday.
每周三 有优惠
Give twice as much as ye receive on our most sacred of days.
在这个神圣的日子要泰献
Every Wednesday.
每个周三
Large adult entertainment section in the back.
有大量成人录像带在那
That's just nasty.
真够恶心的
-What's with the video card? -Don't know.
租片卡怎么回事 不知道
-The watch? -A reminder.
你为什么留下块表 提醒自己
-Of what? -Can't remember.
提醒自己 不记得了
Guess.
猜
I guess we have till midnight. 59 minutes to figure it out.
我猜我们还剩59分37秒
Look. Here's an idea. Let's stop chasing butt-backwards clues...
瞧 我有个主意 我们别再找 这些麻烦的线索
..get a couple fission carbonizers and get our headquarters back.
抄起家伙杀进总部 一切不就都解决了
It's all about to make sense, kid.
谜底就快揭晓了
Is this card valid?
这卡能用吗
-This card hasn't been used in years. -I've been away on business.
这张卡从来没用过 都好几年了 我出差去了
-Billions of frequent flier miles. -Try and use them.
累积了几亿里程 我试试看
l wanted to go to Cambodia. You can get a lobster dinner for a dollar.
我一直想去束埔案 那里龙虾大餐只要1美元
The airlines black out holidays. It's a conspiracy, I'm sure, 1 mean--
里程数在假日不可以用 你必须多时 一个周末这根本就是一个阴谋 为什么
Can you tell us anything about the account?
账户什么情况
You never checked out a tape.
你从来没有租过带子
You reserved one once, but you never picked it up.
你预约了 但从来没来拿过
-Newton. -There's a rat in the toilet.
纽顿 而所有只大老鼠 把马桶堵住了
It's all stopped up. You're gonna have to pee in the sin--
所以我只能去外面方便了
-Still think I'm paranoid? -Yeah.
还说我有妄想症 是的
Gentlemen, my name is Newton. Il run the place. Seen any aliens lately?
各位 我叫做纽顿 我是老板 最近见过外星人吗
-You need professional help. -He's getting it. It's not working.
你需要看医生 他去看了 不过没用
Okay, so, new case, huh?
0K 新的案子 表
Episode 27, Light of Zartha.
第27集 萨塔之光
Got it.
在这
Jarra, it's a sin they've kept a genius like you locked away.
贾拉 你这样的天才不该被关起来
Their agent Jay caught me siphoning ozone to sell on the black market.
那个臭小子 J 他居然告发哲售臭氧层
They're touchy about global warming.
他们担心全球变暖 帮有我做件事
I need a spacecraft that can travel 300 times the speed of light.
找一稻飞船 需要300倍光速
I'll give you whatever you want.
找到了 你要什么都可以
-Give me Jay. We'll call it even. -Groovy.
别的不要 只要J 成交
You've got till midnight.
午夜前给我搞定
Gatbot, I got a little something special for you.
盖伯 你有一项特殊任务
Newton? Newton, is that you?
纽顿 纽顿 是你吗
Yes, Mom, I'm up here with some friends.
是的 妈妈 我有些朋友来
l wanna have your baby.
我想要个孩子
Would you like some mini-pizza?
要不要吃迷你比萨
You guys want some mini-pizzas? They're good.
要吃迷你披萨吗 很好吃
They're like mini-bagels, with pizza stuff on them.
就像加了比萨料的面包图
She'll put a little fontina cheese on.
她还会加上些奶酪
She has palsy, so she ends up putting a lot of cheese on.
不过她手持 有时候奶酪放太多了
No, thanks, we're cool.
不 谢谢 我们不要
This is it.
就是这个
Finally some hard evidence.
嘿 终于找到物证了
Gentlemen, before I play the tape, one question:
对了 各位 在我播放之前 有个问题
What's up with anal probing?
外星人干嘛老是绑架
Aliens travel billions of light years just to check out our--
我是说 难道他们跨越 几十亿光年就为了
Boy, move.
小子 快放
Okay. Just a question.
好吧 我只是问问
Here is one of their stories that "never happened"...
这是个 从未发生过的故事
...from one of their files that doesn't exist.
因为记载它的档案 不存在
1978, Devastating war of Zartha had raged on for 50 years.
1978年 萨塔星发生战乱 延续整整50年
Looks like Spielberg's work.
嘿 像斯皮尔伯格的电影
But the Zarthans had a great treasure, the Light of Zartha.
萨塔星最珍贵的宝物 萨塔之光
A source of power so awesome, it alone...
是一种令人敬畏的力量
...could mean victory and restoration for the Zarthans...
足以让萨堪星人获得胜利
A group of Zarthans made the journey, led by the Keeper of the Light...
萨塔人来到地球 首领是光守护者
...Princess Lauranna.
葛拉 萝拉公主
Lauranna beseeched the Men in Black to help her hide the Light on Earth.
她奶求黑衣人将萨塔之光 藏在地球上
But they could not intervene.
但 他们想难从命
No.
不
It was night.
是在晚上
And it was raining.
在下雨
You've been very wise.
算你聪明
Kay, please. If Serleena takes the Light, it's the end of our world,
K 求你了 如果蛇莲娜得到它 我的星球就完了
If we extend protection for the Light beyond Earth...
尊敬的大使 如果我们收留萨塔之光
...we put Earth in jeopardy. We must remain neutral.
那么地球就会有危险 我们必须保持中立
-Where is it? -We're neutral, remember?
东西在哪 我们是中立的
If you want it, go get it.
你要的话 就拿去
No!
不
And so never knowing it happened...
就这样 尽管无人知晓
the people of Earth were once again saved...
地球人再一次被这些神秘的
..by a secret society of protectors--
保护者拯救
I shouldn't have.
我不该那么做
You never sent it off the planet.
你没把它送走
You hid it here.
藏在地球上
The worm guys.
去虫子那
Are you one of Newton's friends from therapy?
你们都是纽顿的病友吗
-Yes, ma'am, l am. Look here, please. -Would you like some mini-pizz--?
是的 请你看这里 你想要迷你比萨
A neuralyz--
记忆清除
Okay, first, get some contact lenses.
好吧 首先 买副隐形眼镜
Joints look like they pick up cable.
因为 你的眼镜像天线
Second, take her to Cambodia. Get her lobster. Pay more than a dollar.
第二 带她去柬埔寨吃龙虾大餐 别只给一块钱
Third, the second y'all get back from Cambodia...
第三 从柬埔寨回来之后
...move your bum ass out of your mom's house.
从 你母亲家里 搬出去
-Let's go. -Boy, you like 40 years old.
小子 你都40多了
-Agent Jay? -All right, all right.
嘿 JJ 探员
And there ain't no such thing as aliens or Men in Black.
这世上也没有外星人和黑衣人
-You wanna go to Cambodia? -Yeah.
想去柬埔寨吗 好的
Hey, Mom?
妈妈
Communicator, Jay.
通讯器 J
-Laura, it's me. -Jay, we're playing Twister.
葛拉 是我 J 我们在做游戏
What's up, Jay?
怎么了 J
-Quit touching my butt! -l thought it was your face.
嘿 别碰我屁股 我还以为是你脸
They're good at this. They don't have spines.
他们太棒了 都没峭椎骨
They were telling me about Oprah, from Chicago.
他们还懂芝加哥的欧普拉 真有意思
Maybe landed in Chicago.
也许她也是外星人
-Are you wearing a bracelet? -Yeah.
你戴着手链吗
Is it glowing?
对 在发光吗
-It's never done that before. -We're on our way.
是的 以前不会 我们来了
Communicator, Frank.
请接 法兰克
Deactivate the lockdown. We're headed to the worm guys. We found the Light.
法兰克 解除封锁状态 我们正在去虫子之家 我想我们找到光了
Got it, Jay. Scrad?
收到 J 斯凯得
Bitch.
贱人
Why didn't you say I love you?
不说 我爱你
-He's a dog. I don't even like him. -No, the girl. You're sweet on her.
它是狗 我才不爱它 不 那女孩你喜欢 K 我只是. . .
That's why you didn't neuralyze her. You got emotionally involved.
所以你没消除她的记忆 你对她有感情
-Like you did with Lauranna? -I put the entire planet in danger.
就像你和芝拉 我对她的感情 让地球陷入危险期
I don't want to see you making my mistakes.
我不想你和我犯同样的错误
Laura?
葛拉
Damn!
该死
Never stood half a chance.
上帝啊 他们毫无还手之力
Oh, boy.
哦 天啊
That's gonna leave a scar.
会留下伤疤的
-Where's Laura? -MiB headquarters.
葛拉在哪 星际总部
-Some dumb two-headed guy. -They got the bracelet.
也许已经被他们杀了 他们得到手链了
We got 39 minutes. You guys...
我们还有39分钟 你们要
.. pull yourselves together.
振作起来
Damn.
该死
That's feeling better.
哦 感觉好多了
-Hey, guys, wait up! -Let me grab my drink!
嘿嘿 伙计 等等 我们 让我拿杯饮料
Serleena has the bracelet. Why take Laura?
蛇莲娜得到手链 为什么抓葛拉
She also wants me.
他想要抓我
-What's the book say? -We're off book. I say split some wigs.
守则上怎么说 管不了那么多 我们冲进去
-We need wig-splitting weapons. -Got them.
你需要强大火力支援 有了
Paw Paw's coming to visit me. Hello, Paw Paw.
噢 波波要来找我了
Paw Paw and ZuZu love to see what's going on in the garden.
哈罗 波波 波波和苏苏喜欢去花园
Don't worry, folks. I used to live here. Came to pick up a few things.
别担心 我以前住这 来拿些东西
See you.
再见
Which could be the next 28 minutes, so get to loving and cherishing.
没见过什么武器或者什么看虫 有生之年要互敬互爱
And she can stay up as late as she want...
小朋友多晚睡都没关系
..and have cookies and candy and stuff.
让她随便吃饼干和糖果
Four minutes to launch.
4分钟后发射
-Your ship is ready. -Good. Send it to Kyloth now.
飞船准备好了 好 出发去卡罗瑟星
Ready, guys?
准备好了吗
Lock and load, baby.
子弹上膛 宝贝
-You ready, kid? -Kid?
预备 小子
l saved the world from a Kreelon invasion.
当你帮人贴邮票的时候 我击退了奎朗人的入侵
They're the Backstreet Boys of the universe. They throw snowballs?
奎朗人是出了名的宇宙小混混 他们能干嘛 扔雪球
Know what you're doing?
你干嘛
I'm about to attack one of the most feared aliens...
啊 我要跟四条虫和一个邮差
.. with four worms and a mailman. Let's make it hot.
去对付宇宙最大的恶棍了
No, no, wait!
咱们来热身 不 不 等等
A code 101 lockdown!
总部 全被 封锁了
The building gets pressurized. Nothing in, nothing out. I knew that.
我知道 整幢大楼被加压 我知道 我知道
Yeah, you knew. Front and center, worms!
是啊 你知道 虫子们过来
You got it.
来了
It's about time you guys got here. That lady is causing all kinds of hell.
你们早就应该来了 那个漂亮女人把这搞的一团精
Yummy. Someone I need to eat.
哦 好啊 有人送上门来了
Get to the launch pad. The bracelet shows the departure point.
快去发射台 手链会显示出发点 千万不要回来找我
-Do not come back for me. -What?
这是命令 什么意思啊
Do not come back for me.
不要 回来 找我
-Worm guys, give me some cover fire. -Too scared, can't move.
虫子们 开枪掩护 我 好可怕啊”我动不了
Go!
走
-Limber. -Go to subcontrol panel 7-R-Delta.
漂亮 快找到控制台的7RD主板
-Shut off power so they can't take off. -Can't. Too scared.
切断发射台的电源 不行 我好怕
-That way. -Away from the bullets.
哦 这样 小心躲开子弹
No problem.
没问题 我来了
Nice to see you again, Kay.
又见面了 K
-Three minutes to launch. -Jay!
3分钟后发射 4
Three minutes to launch.
3分钟后发射
Hello, Jay. Long time.
久违啦 4
Jarra! What's up, man? You look great.
贾拉 气色不错啊 关了几年
-What's it been? Five years? -And 42 days.
5年 雯42天 托你的福
You count every one when you're locked away.
足监狱的时候我每天都数着
Over our dead titanium bodies!
除非从我尸体上过
Two minutes.
两分钟
Let's play this one by ear.
了呢 可能要久一点
-l should have vaporized you before. -You really did love Lauranna.
我上次应该干掉你 你真的很爱萝拉 对吗 你这个大白阁
Just go, I'll be fine!
2分钟后发射 快光 我没事
What you talking about? I'm winning.
什么 我就要赢了
Jarra, you are under arrest for being that ugly...
贾拉 你被捕了 因为长得太丑
..and for making that many copies. Surrender!
还克隆了那么多 投降吧
l want him in pieces.
让他碎尸万段
Jarra Jr. is going, going...
小页拉飞啊呀 飞 飞
..gone!
啊啊
-Rectum. -Damn near killed him!
哇赛 他差点没命 绝对令人难忘
Never get tired of that one.
同意 怎么切断电源啊
-Where do we shut off the power? -Don't know.
我不知道 管他呢
-I'm fine. I'll be there in a minute. -No, he won't.
葛拉 再等一下 我马上就过来 你休想
Down to one now, Jarra!
只剩一个了
Thirty seconds to launch.
30秒后发射
Fifteen seconds to launch.
15秒后发射
Ten seconds to launch.
10秒后发射
Launch terminated.
发射 中止
-What did you mean, leave you? -Well, he took your gun.
我怎么会丢下你呢 他抢走你的枪
Cracked your head. Slammed you across the room.
对 打你的脑袋 还有 把你有电出去
-Half the time you were on your back. -Look, that's how I fight.
打得你满地改 那是我的战术
You've lost, you insignificant speck.
你输了 你这个窝囊废
You've wasted 25 years of my time, and for what?
你足足浪费了25年时光 为了什么
The total annihilation of Zartha. All because you went mushy.
萨塔星将被摧毁 这一切都是因为你犯的错
I'll give you one last chance to surrender, you slimy invertebrate.
最后再给你一次投降的机会 你这个卡罗瑟疏虫
-What are you gonna do to stop me? -Not me. Him.
你打算怎么阻止我 不是我 是他
Your flight's been canceled.
你的航班取消了
Shut down power. Shut down power. Buttons, buttons. I'm guessing...
关闭电源 关闭电源 按钮 按钮 到底是哪个 咽 对了
-Worms! -Sorry.
虫子 对不起
-Give me the bracelet. -I'm going with you.
快把手链给我 我跟你去 给我手链
Everybody in the car. Everybody.
大家上车 我不认为她 上车
This bracelet is what everybody's been after?
没想到蛇莲娜竟然要这手链
It's often something small.
在很多时候 小东西很重要
It's not the Light. It tells us the departure point.
这不是萨塔之光 它只是指出出发点 什么
If we don't get there in 11 minutes...
如果我们不能在11分15秒以内赶到
.. that bracelet will go nuclear and destroy Earth.
这手链就会爆炸 毁灭地球
What?!
什么
Hello.
哈罗
-Wait. -l know what I'm doing.
K 不 我知道
Damn.
该死
-Modified to hyper-speed! -Seat belts.
这车改装过 让我来 安全带
What's that?
那是什么
At hyper-speed, you have to use the navigational stalk.
高速行驶时 要使用操控器 好吧
Toggle switches for the ailerons. Joysticks for the stabilizer and rudder.
用开关切换左右辟 用摇杆来控制速度和稳定性 好的
I just want you to know--
我只想让你知道
Hold on to that for one second.
有什么话等一下 再和我说
Computer, worms.
电脑 接虫子
I said, "Bitch, if you don't want me to kick your skinny Zone Diet ass...
我说姜子 如果你不想被我捷得 满地找牙的话
-...turn around and exit the planet." -Frank, where are you?
就乖乖的滚蛋 法兰克 你在哪里
Main hall, egg display.
大堂里 指挥中心
We're taking fire. Kay pushed the red button.
我们被攻击 K按下了红色按钮
Computer at MiB can destroy bogey. I'll walk you through it.
总部的电脑 可以追踪击落飞行物 我来教你
Jay? Frank. You were the best darn partner a Remoolian could ever have.
我的天 J 是法兰克 我有没有说过 你们两个是最好的搭档
Godspeed.
一切顺利
Frank? Frank?
法兰克 法兰克 法兰克
Okay, here we go, automatic pilot.
好吧 这样吧 自动驾驶
-It is not automatic piloting. -He doesn't operate at hyper-speed.
这不是自动驾驶 高速行驶时没用的
-l could use a steering wheel! -This is what we got.
我要的是方向盘 可是 没有方向盘 只有这玩意
-Didn't you ever have a Game Boy? -What's that?
你从来没玩过游戏机吗 什么游戏机
You know what? Move.
受不了你 让开
That is not the navigational stalk!
这个东西可不是择杆
Okay, straight down.
好吧 直接向下
Idiots.
白痴
Subway may not be the best place to lose her.
你钻进隧道也甩不掉她 趴
-Where is he? -He?
他在哪儿 谁
Jeff. Hang on!
杰弗 抓紧了
Oops.
WO0O0OPS
Teeth.
大牙
Running out of time, Kay. Where is the Light?
我们快没时间了 萨塔之光在哪
-What? -What, I'm the Light?
什么 什么我是光
-No. No way. -You have a planet to save.
不 不可能 你要拯救你的星球
You're mistaken. I work at a pizzeria.
你们找错人了 我在比萨店工作
Two days ago, I was running a post office. You are who you are.
我以前只是个普通的邮差 你得接受事实
Laura, you are the Light.
葛拉 你 就是萨塔人之光
The leader of your people. Their spirit and their hope.
是萨塔人的领袖 他们全部希望
The power is within you to save a planet.
你有力量拯救星球
I protected you until it was your time. Your time is now.
25年来我一直保护着你 现在是时候了
You will save a world. You know things before they happen.
现在你要去拯救家园 不 我不可能 你能未小先知
-I'm a Libra. -You're Zarthan.
我是天秤座 你是萨塔人
-When you get sad, it rains. -Lots of people get sad when it rains.
你觉得悲伤的时候天会下雨 很多人下雨时 觉得悲伤
It rains because you're sad, baby.
会下雨 因为你难过
It's not fair.
这不公平
Never is.
人生如此
We are who we are...
我们必须做自己
..even if we sometimes forget.
尽管也许并不愿意
Jeff, lam so not in the mood for you!
杰弗 我没心情搭理你 快回隧道去
Get back in the subway! Now!
快
That's not good.
看起来不妙
Wait! No!
等等 不
Jay!
J
I cannot emphasize strongly enough how much we need you on that transport.
你一定要立刻上船离开 别再犹天了公主
Laura! You have to go!
葛拉 你必须走
Go. He's fine. He does this all the time.
走 他没事 他经常这个样子
Nope!
不
About to lay the smackdown on your candy ass.
我要狠狠的接扁你
Laura! It's your destiny!
葛拉 这是你的使命
l was talking, Kay!
我还能说话
Hey! No biting.
K 嘿 别 咬我
If you don't go, we all die.
你再不走 我们都完了
You're just as beautiful as your mother.
啊 你和你母亲一样美
Kay? A little help?
帮帮有我K
Kay?
K
Might I suggest a bigger gun?
可以用大一点的枪吗
-Kid? -Yeah.
小子 在
-Thanks for bringing me back. -No problem.
谢谢你带我回来 不客气
Why didn't you tell me?
你怎么不早说
Would you have let her go?
说了你会让她走
So, what's it like on the outside? Not doing this every day?
当普通人感觉如何 不用每天如此
It's nice.
不错
Sleep late on the weekends. Watch the Weather Channel.
周末睡懒觉 看看气象频道
I did miss this city.
我怀念这个城市
So Laura is Princess Lauranna's daughter.
葛拉 真是萝拉公主的女儿
-Did y'all--? -MiB's a mess. Let's go, kid.
你有没有 总部一团糟 我们走吧
Let's go?
就这样
Thousands of people in New York and New Jersey saw our little event.
有成千上万人刚刚目睹了这一切
Plan needs to be thought out. Plan needs to be cool. What you--?
我们要详细的计划 一定要周全
Kid, I'll get you trained yet.
小子 你还有得学呢
I want one of those.
我也想要一个
Damn!
郁癌
-How you doing? -I'm good.
你还好吗 我很好
We've all been there. The girl is gone and it hurts. Wanna talk?
大家都碰到过这事 爱人走了 很伤心 谈谈
-No. -l can help.
不 我想帮你
No.
不用
Still sulking?
还在难过吗
-No. -Yeah.
谁
You miss her. It happens to all of us. I knew this hot young thing.
你想念她 这一切很正常 我曾经遇到过一个女孩
When our bodies were in the positions of the Kamasutra--
我们在一起度过了很多美好的时光
Zed!
Z
Come on, man! Damn!
别说下去了 该死的
I'll tell you about dames.
嘿 J」对女孩子我有经验
They say they want to be scratched, but they really want:
他们说想要这个 其实心里想要另外的
Hey! Frank.
法兰克
What? Still sitting shiva? Want my advice?
怎么 还难过吗
No. No advice.
想听建议吗 不 不想听
No talking.
别再烦我
Hell, no.
包括你
Fellas, ! swear, I'm fine.
各位 我都说了 我很好
All hail Jay! All hail Jay!
J 万风 J 万穷
-l brought them from Grand Central. -Why put them in my locker?
我把他们从中央车站带来了 你干嘛都放在我柜子里
l thought it would put things in perspective.
我想让你开心一下
It's kind of sad. We need to let them out.
K 别把它们关在里面 应该给他们自由
They need to know the world is bigger than that.
他们应该知道世界其实很大很大
Still a rookie.
(危险 危险请勿打开)